Oh, that mansion.
O malikâne.
It's at the top of that hill.
Şu tepenin zirvesinde.
I see. Thank you.
Anladım, teşekkürler.
No problem.
Rica ederim.
Roses, eh?
Güller.
Just like the palace in Sleeping Beauty.
Uyuyan Güzel'deki saray gibi.
My name is Anna.
Benim adım Anna.
Anna Liebert.
Anna Liebert.
Best of luck, mister great detective.
Bol şans harika dedektif.
She was worried that something awful might happen to you.
Başına kötü bir şey gelmesinden endişeleniyordu!
You see, I feel the same way that your mother feels.
Ben de tıpkı annen gibi hissediyorum.
Anna…
Anna.
Were you just dreaming,
Rüya mı görüyordun?
Detective Suk?
Dedektif Suk.
Huh? Who are you?
Ne? Sen kimsin?
I'm Lunge, an inspector with the BKA.
Ben Lunge, Federal Kriminal Polis Ofisi dedektifiyim.
The BKA?
-Federal Kriminal Polis Ofisi mi? -Sorun değil, rahat ol.
I didn't come here to arrest you.
Buraya seni tutuklamaya gelmedim.
This is quite a nice hospital room.
Burası çok güzel bir hastane odası.
I went to several hospitals with connections
Eski Çekoslovakya gizli polisiyle bağlantısı olan birkaç hastane gezdim,
You're being treated quite well.
Sana çok iyi bakılıyor.
You must be very important to the former secret police.
Eski gizli polis için çok önemli olmalısın.
No, I was simply--
Hayır, ben sadece…
I already know all about you.
Hakkındaki her şey biliyorum.
The beating death of Inspector Zeman who had connections with the secret police.
Gizli polisle bağlantısı olan Dedektif Zeman'ı döverek öldürdün.
The poisoning deaths of the commissioner
Prag Karakolu başkomiseri ve iki dedektifini zehirleyerek öldürdün.
The shooting deaths of the two detectives who were tailing you.
Peşindeki iki dedektifi silahla öldürdün.
You're being pursued as a person of interest in all these murders.
Tüm bu cinayetlerde baş şüpheli olarak aranıyorsun.
Judging from just circumstantial evidence, you're the murderer in all these cases.
Dolaylı delillere bakılırsa tüm bu davalarda katil sensin.
You're wrong. I didn't do any of those things!
Yanılıyorsun. Hiçbirini ben işlemedim.
Then was it the tall man, Grimmer,
Grimmer denen o uzun boylu adam mı işledi?
who Inspector Zeman questioned before he was beaten to death?
Dedektif Zeman'ın öldürülmeden önce sorguladığı adam.
It wasn't Mr. Grimmer either! He's not that kind of person!
Bay Grimmer da işlemedi. O öyle birisi değil.
Then who is the murderer?
O zaman katil kim?
I bet you know, don't you?
Eminim biliyorsundur, değil mi?
I bet you know who the murderer is.
Katilin kim olduğunu biliyorsun, değil mi?
That's ridiculous.
Saçmalık bu.
If I knew who it was, I wouldn't be in this state.
Katili bilseydim bu durumda olmazdım.
I've been betrayed over and over.
Defalarca ihanete uğradım.
I've been framed for murder and the police are after me now.
Bana cinayet kumpası kuruldu ve şimdi polis peşimde.
I've had enough of this. I'm sick of being stabbed in the back!
Canıma tak etti. Sırtımdan bıçaklanmaktan usandım!
You're a detective, right?
Dedektifsin, değil mi?
As a detective, you must calmly dissect and investigate everything.
Bir dedektif olarak her şeyi sakince, didik didik incelemelisin.
Even at the cost of your happiness,
Karşılığında mutluluğundan olacağını bilsen de
you must keep a level head as you dig up the truth.
soğukkanlılıkla gerçeği aramalısın.
If you don't want to be betrayed anymore,
Bir daha sırtından bıçaklanmak istemiyorsan
then suspect the person you least want to suspect.
en son şüphelenmek isteyeceğin insandan şüphelen.
Who said you could see him?
Görüşebileceğinizi kim söyledi?
Bring me to your boss.
Beni patronuna götür.
Tell him I want to talk about the rose mansion.
Güllü malikâne hakkında konuşmak istediğimi söyle.
I know he'll want to talk to me about that.
Bu konuda konuşmak isteyeceğini biliyorum.
Inspector Lunge of the BKA.
Federal Kriminal Polis Ofisinden Dedektif Lunge.
I've checked out who you are and about your past.
Kim olduğunuzu, geçmişinizi kontrol ettim.
I've also
Eski rejim sırasında
heard all kinds of rumors about you during the old regime, Captain Ranke.
hakkınızda türlü dedikodular da duydum Yüzbaşı Ranke.
I've heard you're also the de facto leader of
Eski Çekoslovakya gizli polisinin
the former Czechoslovakia secret police.
fiili lideri olduğunuzu da duydum.
Things have been quite difficult for you recently.
Şu ara işler sizin için çok zor oldu.
Thank you for your concern.
Endişeniz için teşekkürler.
I'm envious of people like you who can take long vacations.
Sizin gibi uzun tatillere çıkabilen insanlara imreniyorum.
I heard that two years ago,
Duydum ki iki sene önce
your aggressive investigation of the secretary of Representative Boltzmann,
Temsilci Boltzmann'ın sekreterini agresif biçimde soruşturmanız
a candidate to lead the German Democratic Party, led to his suicide.
Alman Demokratik Parti lider adayının intihara sürüklemiş.
You have to be more skillful than that to get far in this world.
Böyle ilerlediğinize göre çok yetenekli olmalısınız.
You and your people were foolish.
Sizinkilerle aptallık ettiniz.
If you'd taken a softer line during democratization
Demokratikleşme sırasında daha ılımlı bir yol izleyip
you could be leading this country now as the shadow president.
gölgedeki başkan olarak bu ülkeyi siz yönetiyor olurdunuz.
But now, the fear that the public has of your people is just an illusion.
Ama şimdi halkın sizden korktuğu düşünesi sadece bir hayal.
I see. You're quite sharp.
Anlıyorum, çok zekisiniz.
So, what brings you and your smarts to me?
Bu zekâyla bana gelmenizin sebebi ne?
As you already know, I'm on an extended vacation,
Bildiğiniz gibi uzun bir tatildeyim.
so I'm partly here for pleasure.
Yani kısmen keyif için geldim.
I'm looking for something.
Birini arıyorum.
I'm looking for the embodiment of true fear.
Korkunun vücut bulmuş hâlini arıyorum.
I want to know if a true demon was born
Gerçek bir iblisin sizin yarattığınız bir illüzyondan
So, this is about the Red Rose Mansion.
Kırmızı Güllü Malikâne için geldiniz yani.
I had to search quite a lot before I found that mansion.
O malikâneyi bulabilmek için çok araştırma yapmam gerekti.
That's because the author of this book had many pen names.
Çünkü bu kitabın yazarının bir sürü takma adı var.
The Nameless Monster.
İsimsiz Canavar.
The author's name is Emil Scherbe
Yazarın adı Emil Scherbe.
His address was an apartment in an old building in Prague.
Adresi Prag'taki eski binadaki bir daire. Daireyi farklı bir şirket kiralıyor.
The address for Klaus Poppe is an old farm house in the suburbs.
Klaus Poppe'nin adresi banliyöde eski bir çiftlik evi.
But it's already been torn down.
Ama orası çoktan yıkılmış.
Jakob Vyrobek's address is also just a rental space.
Jakov Vyrobek'in adresi de kiralık bir ev.
But you eventually found…
Ama şeyi sonunda buldunuz mu,
Franz Bonaparta?
Frankz Bonaparta'yı.
What is it with that mansion?
O kişinin bu malikâneyle ne ilgisi var?
Who is Franz Bonaparta?
Franz Bonaparta kim?
No matter how much I search, I can't find anything on him.
Ne kadar araştırsam da ona dair hiçbir şey bulamadım.
Which can only mean that he was one of your people,
Bu da demek oluyor ki o, sizden birisi,
a member of the former Czechoslovakia secret police.
eski Çekoslovakya gizli polisinin bir üyesi.
What do you want to know?
Ne bilmek istiyorsunuz?
I want to know what you know.
Sizin bildiklerinizi bilmek istiyorum.
I know nothing.
Hiçbir şey bilmiyorum.
Except…
Şey hariç…
Yes?
Ne?
I've consciously tried to forget it.
Bilerek unutmaya çalıştım.
I have consciously tried to forget about that mansion.
O malikâneyi bilerek unutmaya çalıştım.
That's why I've never touched or messed with it,
Bu yüzden hiç dokunmadım veya uğraşmadım
and why it still stands there.
ve bu yüzden hâlâ duruyor.
All the political prisoners who were brought there
Oraya götürülen tüm siyasi mahkûmlar
and all the researchers who were there disappeared one day.
ve tüm araştırmacılar bir gün ortadan kayboldu.
That's all I know.
Tüm bildiklerim bu.
What is that wall?
O duvar ne?
What wall?
Ne duvarı?
The other day, I went inside that mansion.
Geçen gün o malikânenin içine girdim.
There's no sign of anyone having entered it.
Kimsenin girdiğine dair bir iz yok.
It's completely abandoned. However,
Tamamen terk edilmiş ama ikinci katın kuzey cephesinde
there's a wall that looks as if it was hastily put up to shut something inside.
bir şeyi içeri kapatmak için aceleyle örülmüşe benzeyen bir duvar var.
Can I tear down that wall?
O duvarı yıkabilir miyim?
What are you frightened of, Captain Ranke?
Neden korkuyorsunuz Yüzbaşı Ranke?
You just might die.
Ölebilirsiniz.
If you get any closer to it,
Daha yaklaşırsanız
both you and I…
siz de ben de
might see what true fear is.
gerçek korkunun ne olduğunu görebiliriz.
Franz Bonaparta, eh?
Franz Bonaparta demek.
I haven't heard that name in a long time.
Bu ismi uzun zamandır duymuyorum.
Do you take milk or sugar in your coffee?
Kahvene süt veya şeker ister misin?
It's fine black.
Sade iyi.
Is something wrong?
Bir sorun mu var?
No. I'm just surprised that a fan of Franz Bonaparta has suddenly shown up.
Hayır, Franz Bonaparta'nın bir hayranının birden ortaya çıkmasına şaşırdım sadece.
I heard about you from Moravia Publishing.
Adınızı Moravia Yayınevi'nden aldım.
Mr. Sovák,
Bay Sovák,
I heard you were Mr. Bonaparta's editor for a long time.
Bay Bonaparta'ya uzun süre editörlük yaptığınızı duydum.
Yes.
Evet
But I was only his editor
ama Klaus Poppe takma adıyla
when he worked under the pen name Klaus Poppe.
yazarlık yaparken editörüydüm sadece.
I'd like to know what kind of person he was.
Nasıl bir insan olduğunu merak ediyorum.
Franz Bonaparta, huh?
Franz Bonaparta demek.
He would come to my home here to discuss his work.
Eserlerini konuşmak için evime gelirdi.
He would sit in that chair there just like you are.
Tıpkı senin gibi o koltuğa otururdu.
He'd often play in the garden with my daughter too.
Sık sık bahçede kızımla oynardı.
But at the time, my daughter said something odd.
Ama o ara kızım tuhaf bir şey söyledi.
She said, "That man is frightening."
"O adam ürkütücü biri" dedi.
But I doubt my daughter remembers anything now
Ama kızım çok küçüktü, bunları hatırlayacağını hiç sanmıyorum.
Was he a member of a government agency then?
O dönem bir devlet kurumuna üye miydi?
He probably was. I figured he was when I worked with him.
Muhtemelen öyledir. Onunla çalışırken anladım.
But his demeanor and the way he talked and dressed
Ama eski bir rejimin devlet memurlarında
had a gentleness and gracefulness that was uncommon
hiç görülmedik biçimde nazik ve zarif tavrı, konuşması
Bonaparta had a doctorate in psychiatry and was also a psychologist.
Bonaparta psikiyatri doktorası yaptı ve ayrıca psikologdu.
He specialized in neurosurgery.
-Beyin cerrahisi üzerine uzmanlaşmış. -Anlıyorum.
Let's see, when did I last see him?
Düşüneyim, onu en son ne zaman gördüm.
I think it was the summer of either 1981 or 1982.
Sanırım 1981 veya 1982 yazındaydı.
That day, he suddenly dropped by here.
O gün birden buraya uğradı.
He talked about his idea for a new book.
Yeni bir kitap fikrinden bahsetti.
I remember now. He appeared rather energetic.
Şimdi hatırladım. Çok enerjikti.
What was the new story about?
Yeni öyküsünün konusu neymiş?
It was about a monster who falls in love.
Âşık olan bir canavar.
It was like a mix of Sleeping Beauty and Beauty and the Beast.
Uyuyan Güzel ve Güzel ve Çirkin karışımı gibiydi.
I rejected it.
İtiraz ettim.
Then just before he left, when he was at the door,
Sonra gitmeden hemen önce, kapıdayken
he said, "Oh, I know. How about this?"
"Buldum, şuna ne dersin? dedi.
Then he turned around and said,
Sonra bana dönüp şöyle dedi,
"A story about a door that must never be opened."
"Asla açılmaması gereken bir kapı hakkında bir öykü"
I asked him,
Şöyle sordum,
"Is there a paradise beyond it? Or does a monster come out?"
"Ardında cennet mi var yoksa arkasından bir canavar mı çıkıyor?"
Then he said,
Sonra şöyle dedi,
"No. Since it must never be opened, I guess it won't make much of a story."
"Hayır, hiç açılmaması gerektiği için sanırım bundan pek bir öykü çıkmaz"
After saying that, he laughed and left.
Bunu söyledikten sonra gülüp gitti.
That was the last time I saw him.
Onu en son o zaman gördüm.
Did you find anything significant about this Bonaparta guy?
Bonaparta denen adam hakkında önemli bir şey buldun mu?
No, I didn't learn much.
Hayır, pek bir şey öğrenemedim.
Mr. Grimmer, what are you doing here?
Grimmer, burada ne yapıyorsun?
I was just admiring the nice weather.
Güzel havanın tadını çıkarıyordum.
Yes, it sure is.
Gerçekten güzel.
I knew it.
Biliyordum.
Hello? Police?
Alo, polis mi?
I'm Sovák. I live near Schwaig Square.
Ben Sovák. Schwaig Meydanı civarında oturuyorum.
A man just came to my place
Az önce evime bir adam geldi.
who I think is wanted as a person of interest
Sanırım Almanya'daki seri cinayetlerin
in those serial murders in Germany.
baş şüphelisi.
Yes, he was Japanese. That neurosurgeon Dr. Tenma.
Evet, Japon'du. Dr. Tenma adındaki o beyin cerrahı.
JAPANESE DOCTOR IN DÜSSELDORF
JAPON DOKTOR DÜSSELDORF'TA
Ethanol?
Etanol mu?
It smells like disinfectant.
Dezenfektan gibi kokuyor.
Death… Several people… died here.
Ölüm… Burada birkaç kişi ölmüş.
Ten people…
10 kişi…
Maybe 20…
Belki de 20…
No, even more.
Hayır, daha da fazla.
That woman…
Bu kadın…
She's the one from the sketchbook.
Eskiz defterindeki kadınlardan.
The mother of those twins.
O ikizlerin annesi.
Hey, if we don't hurry, the older kids will take the soccer field!
Hey, acele etmezsek futbol sahasını büyükler kapar!
Hurry up, Milosz!
Çabuk ol Milosz.
Okay.
Tamam.
Go! Counter attack!
Koş! Kontra atak!
Oh no! Pull back! They're charging for the goal!
Hayır, geri çekil! Kaleye gidiyorlar!
Oh no! They'll score!
Olamaz, gol atacaklar!
Go!
Koşun!
-Woah! -Milosz!
-Aman! -Milosz!
You okay, Milosz?
İyi misin Milosz?
Wake up, Milosz!
Uyan Milosz.
Nice save, Milosz!
Güzel çıkardın Milosz.
Way to clear it! You stopped them from scoring!
Çok iyi çıkardın. Gol attırmadın.
-What? -Way to go, Milosz!
-Ne? -Aferin Milosz!
He's smiling. I guess he's all right now.
Gülümsüyor, sanırım artık iyi.
What do you think, Dr. Tenma?
Ne dersin Dr. Tenma?
I agree.
Bence de.
Mr. Grimmer, aren't you going to talk to Milosz and the other kids?
Grimmer, Milosz ve diğer çocuklarla konuşmayacak mısın?
I figured out why I'm not good at soccer.
Futbolda neden iyi olmadığımı anladım.
I'm not a team player.
Takım oyuncusu değilim.
What happens to Detective Jan Suk now?
Dedektif Jan Suk'a şimdi ne olacak?
He's wanted as a person of interest in the murders,
O cinayetlerde baş şüpheli olarak aranıyor.
which is the same as being kicked out of society.
Toplumdan dışlanmakla aynı sayılır.
Even if he turned himself in, how could he prove his innocence?
Teslim olsa bile masum olduğunu nasıl kanıtlayacak?
How can he prove the existence of this blonde woman who left the scene?
Olay yerinden ayrılan o sarışın kadının var olduğunu nasıl kanıtlayacak?
He's in the same situation as you are.
Seninle aynı durumda.
But there is one difference.
Ama aranızda tek bir fark var.
I'll be seeing you, Dr. Tenma.
Görüşeceğiz Dr. Tenma.
What?
Ne?
As for these murders,
Bu cinayetlere gelirsek,
there is one person who knows all the particulars about them.
cinayetlerin tüm detaylarını bilen sadece bir kişi var.
He's right here.
O kişi tam burada.
What if I sent something like this to the police?
Polise böyle bir şey göndersem nasıl olur?
What's this?
Bu ne?
It's a letter from a serial murderer.
Seri katilden bir mektup.
It's a detailed description of things that have been kept secret
Olayları sadece asıl katilin bilebileceği, sır olarak saklanan detaylarla anlattığı
But if you send this to the police, then you'll be arrested!
Ama bu mektubu polise gönderirsen tutuklanırsın!
This Grimmer person will somehow make his way back to Germany.
Grimmer denen bu kişi bir şekilde Almanya'ya dönecek.
I'm sure the police will come after him,
Polis eminim onun peşine düşer
but this Grimmer guy will be able to get away from them.
ama Grimmer onlardan kaçabilecek.
You see, he was originally quite a talented spy.
Grimmer aslında epey yetenekli bir casustu.
But you'll end up being a suspect on the run your whole life!
Ama şüpheli olup ömrün boyunca kaçak yaşarsın.
I don't mind.
Sorun değil.
You see, this Grimmer person never really existed anyway.
Grimmer denen bu kişi aslında hiç var olmadı.
He's a person someone forced me to be.
Birileri beni Grimmer olmaya zorladı.
Even if Grimmer is suspected of murder all his life,
Grimmer ömrü boyu cinayet zanlısı olsa da
it doesn't bother me at all.
bu beni hiç ilgilendirmez.
So, what do you think of doing things this way, Dr. Tenma?
Böyle yapmaya ne dersin Dr. Tenma?
Oh, never mind. Don't tell me.
Boş ver, söyleme.
You're going to that rose mansion now, aren't you?
Şimdi o güllü malikâneye gidiyorsun, değil mi?
Yes.
Evet.
You may finally be close to your goal.
Hedefine nihayet yaklaşmış olabilirsin.
No, I'm not so sure.
Hayır, pek emin değilim.
I'm sure you wouldn't listen if I told you not to be rash.
Acele etme desem bile beni dinlemeyeceğine eminim.
However, just don't die.
Ama ölme yeter.
Mr. Grimmer.
Grimmer.
Like we promised when we crossed the Czech border,
Çek sınırında birbirimize söz verdik.
when we meet again somewhere, let's have a picnic.
Bir daha görüşürsek piknik yapalım.
We'll fish for trout in a beautiful spot…
Çok güzel bir yerde alabalık tutarız.
and enjoy good wine and cheese.
Güzel bir şarap açar, peynir yeriz.
Let's meet again.
Tekrar görüşelim.
I guess from now on, I'll always be frightened by that sound.
Sanırım şu andan itibaren bu sesten korkacağım.
Give it back!
Geri ver!
Ow! It hurts!
Acıdı!
What's wrong? Let me see that.
Ne oldu? Bir bakayım.
It's just a scrape.
Sıyrık sadece.
I'll put some disinfectant on it.
Üzerine dezenfektan dökeyim.
Ouch!
Acıyor!
You're a big boy. Tough it out.
Kocaman adamsın. Dayan.
There. You're very brave.
Bitti. Çok cesursun.
Kenzo Tenma, right?
Kenzo Tenma, değil mi?
We're the police.
Biz polisiz.
Come with us to the station.
Bizimle karakola geliyorsun.
Subtitle translation by: Brian Athey
Alt yazı çevirmeni: Ömür Gencer